A Guide to Records of the Office of the Attorney General of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1974-1994 (bulk 1990-1993)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Office of the Attorney General of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1974-1994 (bulk 1990-1993)
The Library of Virginia
35539
8.6 cu. ft. (25 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1990-1994: Wilder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78, 2.2-3800, and 2.2-3705.1-8. Types of previous restricted information may include, but are not limited to: privacy protected information and attorney-client privileged material.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder on October 31, 1996.
Biographical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
The Office of the Attorney General is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state Government. During the Wilder Administration, the Office was headed by Mary Sue Terry, until she resigned in 1993 to run for governor. Stephen D. Rosenthal, formerly the chief deputy assistant general, replaced her and served until 1994. The attorney general was assisted by a chief deputy attorney general and four deputy attorneys general. The Attorney General's Office was responsible for providing legal advice and representation in court for the governor and state government; providing legal advice and official opinions to members of the General Assembly and local government officials; defending the state in cases of criminal appeals and suits against the state; defending the constitutionality of state laws; and collecting money owed to various state institutions.
Scope and Content
Records of the Office of the Attorney General, 1974-1994 (bulk 1990-1993), during the administration of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder. The collection is housed in 25 boxes and includes correspondence, court records, memorandums, newspaper clippings, reports, summons, subpoenas, and other documents. The collection is arranged into xx series: Series I: Case Files, Series II:
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: Series I: Case Files, Series II: General Files, Series III: Subpoenas and Summons, and Series IV: Settlements.
Contents List
- Series I: Case Files, 1990-1993., Extent: 4.9 cu. ft. (14 boxes). (Box 1-14)
  The Case Files series is housed in 14 boxes, and is arranged alphabetically by folder title. It includes four subseries. Subseries have been designated for A: Case files; B: Davis Cases; C: Koch Carbon; and D: Terry v. Wilder. The series consists of correspondence, court records, memorandums, reports, and other documents.
  - Subseries A: Case Files, 1990-1993., 2.1 cu. ft. (6 boxes) (Box 1-6)
    This subseries is housed in 6 boxes and includes correspondence, court records, memorandums, reports, and other documents. The cases are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - ACLU v. Murray, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A. H. Robins - Collections Matter, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alfaro, Pilar v. John Milliken, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Glenn v. L. Douglas Wilder et. al., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Argabite, William T. v. City of Newport News, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Avtex Suit, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bankruptcy Case #86-00352-N, Overholser, Thomas J., AKA Kopy Kat Instant Printing, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Barnett v. Grizzard, et al, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - B&B Steel v. Dept. of Labor and Industry, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Boyd, Rodney L. v. Commonwealth of Virginia and SVTC, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bracey, Linda Joy v. Industrial Commission of Virginia, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Burnson v. Freeman, and Cipollone v. Liggett Group Inc., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Canadian Pacific and D&H Corp. Interstate Commerce Commission, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Castle, Thomas v. Andrew Jallah, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Clinchfield Coal Co. v. UMWA, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Clottis Leon Carter v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Committee of Citizens for Property Rights, Appellants v. Chesapeake Bay Local Asst. Board, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia v. Brian N. Hogan, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Commonwealth v. Hudnall, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Commonwealth v. Stedson Linkous, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Commonwealth v. McLaughlin, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Commonwealth v. Moody, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Commonwealth v. Simon, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Commonwealth v. Sindram, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia ex. rel. State Water Control Board v. Elfco Association, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Corning Glass v. Dept. of Taxation, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Cox v. Blalock, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Crestar v. SEAA/VELA, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Cummings v. Cummings; Cummings v. Bryant, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Delaware v. New York, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Delaware v. New York, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Delong, Wayne K. v. Charles E. Thompson, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dennis v. Higgins, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Donahue, John Patrick v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dykes, Marcia and Osgood Tower v. NOVA Trans. Dist. Commission and Fairfax Board of Supervisors, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Extra's Inc. v. VEC and Gerald Carter, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Finley, Lantha D. v. Virginia Tech Foundation and Commonwealth of Virginia, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - FMC Corp. v. Holiday and Trinova Corp. v. Michigan, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Fraternal Order of Eagles v. Virginia ABC Board Tip Jars, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Freeman, Lance Tyler - Personal Injury Case, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Garraghty v. Williams, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Gibbs v. Murray et. al., 1990 (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gibbs v. Murray et. al., 1990 (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gibbs v. Murray et. al., 1990 (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Green v. Murray, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Gregory v. Ashcroft, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Habib Estate v. Blanchard et al, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hafer v. Melo, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Harriman, Rebecca v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Home Property Owners Association v. L. Douglas Wilder et al, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Howlett v. Rose, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ingersoll-Rand Co. v. McClendon, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Jamerson, W. E. v. Howard P. Anderson - Halifax Redistricting, 1991 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Jamerson, W. E. v. Howard P. Anderson - Halifax Redistricting, 1991 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Jeffries, Jesse Wilson v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1990-1992 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Jeffries, Jesse Wilson v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1990-1992 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jeffries, Jesse Wilson v. Titius and Seius, et al, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, Mark v. Edward Murray, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Kansas and Missouri v. Kansas Power and Light Co., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Kim-Stan, Inc., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Koochekzadeh v. Farmer, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Marion Litle League, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Martinez, Pedro Juan v. Commonwealth, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Moody, M., J. Greenhill, and W. Witherspoon v. Virginia Dept. of Transportation, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Neblett v. Commonwealth et al, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - North Carolina v. Exxon, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Onan, Lawrence J. v. Elmer Clinton Hodge - Voluntary Dimissal, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Phelps, Ziba Bennett v. Sovran Bank, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Pittson Coal v. Commonwealth, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Planned Parenthood v. Casey, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Pucett, Robert D. v. Social Security Office of Disability and Internal Operations, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Ramsay, Todd Lee v. K. W. Graham, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Recycle Systems Proposed Settlement, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Rudnicki, Chester v. U.S. Dept. of Justice, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Schoof v. Dept. of Youth and Family Services - Kehoe, 1992 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Schoof v. Dept. of Youth and Family Services - Kehoe, 1992 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Schoof v. Charles J. Kehoe - Civil Action, 1993 (1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Schoof v. Charles J. Kehoe - Civil Action, 1993 (2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Schoof v. Charles J. Kehoe - Civil Action, 1993 (3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Schoof v. Charles J. Kehoe - Civil Action, 1993 (4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Small v. Burnette, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Small v. State Board for Community Colleges, et al, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Suter v. Artis Welfare of R.A.V. - Amicus Brief, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Tangier Sound Waterman's Association v. Pruitt, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Taylor v. Commonwealth, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - United Mine Workers of America v. Clinchfield Coal Company, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - U.S. v. Commonwealth of Virginia (Hercules Aerospace), 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - United States v. Commonwealth of Virginia and Virginia Industrial Commission, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - United States v. Sheila McGough, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - VA Hospital Association v. Wilder, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - VHA Litigation, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Beach v. North Carolina (re: Lake Gaston), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Walton, Paul v. Commonwealth of Virginia Dept. of Transportation, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Worrell Enterprises, Inc. v. Taylor, 1990-1991 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Worrell Enterprises, Inc. v. Taylor, 1990-1991 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: Davis Cases, 1989-1993., 1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes) (Box 7-9)
    This subseries is housed in 3 boxes and includes correspondence, court records, memorandums, reports, and other documents. The series consists of cases related to the U.S. Supreme Court's decision in Michigan v. Davis, 1989, which ruled that states could not tax federal retirement benefits if they exempted state pensions from taxation. This led to cases in several states when retired federal employees filed suit seeking refunds for state income taxes, including Henry Harper, et al., v. Virginia Department of Taxation, filed in 1990.
    - Ashland Oil, Inc. v. Caryl National Mines Corp., 1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Beam, James v. Georgia, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Burns, Robert L. v. New Mexico, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Davis Cases, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Davis and Harper Cases, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Davis Cases, Pension Tax Refunds, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Davis Pension Tax Refund Suits, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Davis Related Cases - Status Update and Other Information, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Davis Related Tax Cases, 1989 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Davis Related Tax Cases, 1989 (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Davis v. Michigan Dept. of Treasury, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Duffy v. Wetzler, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Greidinger v. Davis, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Harper v. Virginia Dept. of Taxation, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Harper v. Virginia Dept. of Taxation, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Harper v. Virginia Dept. of Taxation, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Harper, Henry v. Virginia Dept. of Taxation, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Harper et al v. Virginia Dept. of Taxation - Meeting of House Finance Committee, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Hunter, Gerald S. - Request for Refund, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - McKesson v. Florida, and American Trucking Association v. Smith, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Pledger, Jim v. Stanley Bosnick, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Pruitt v. Wilder, Milliken, and Williams (DMV), 1993 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Pruitt v. Wilder, Milliken, and Williams (DMV), 1993 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Sheehy, Edmund F. v. Montana, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Simmons, Gerard - Harper v. Virginia, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - South Carolina Supreme Court Decision, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Update of Davis Related Litigation, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Subseries C: Koch Carbon, 1987-1993., .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes) (Box 10-11)
    This subseries is housed in 2 boxes and includes correspondence, court records, memorandums, reports, and other documents. The cases in this subseries involve Koch Carbon, an affiliate of Koch Industries, Inc. Koch Carbon sued the Commonwealth of Virginia, alleging that the presence of Keen Mountain State Prison compromised their operations.
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1992-1993 (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1992-1993 (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1992-1993 (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1987-1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1987-1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Keen Mountain Prison - Mining, Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1990-1992 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Keen Mountain Prison - Mining, Koch Carbon v. Commonwealth, 1990-1992 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Subseries D: Terry v. Wilder, 1974-1993 (bulk 1992-1993)., 1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes) (Box 12-14)
    This subseries is housed in 3 boxes and includes correspondence, court records, memorandums, reports, and other documents. The cases in this subseries relate to Attorney General Mary Sue Terry's lawsuit against Gov. L. Douglas Wilder. Gov. Wilder attempted to remove Terry as legal counsel for the Virginia Retirement System, citing a conflict of interest. Terry denied that Wilder had the authority to remove or replace her. The initial ruling in Terry's favor was overturned by the Virginia Supreme Court.
    - Olshan, Grundham, Frome, and Rosenzweg v. VRS and SHI, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Terry v. Wilder, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Terry v. Wilder, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Appellant Briefs, 1993 (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Appellant Briefs, 1993 (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Appellant's Reply Brief, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Terry v. Wilder - "Appendix," 1992 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Attorney Fees, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Bill of Complaint Papers, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Brief of Appellee, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Correspondence between Governor and Attorney General, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Correspondence with Jacqueline Epps, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Executive Orders, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Final Decree Papers, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Terry v. Wilder - George B. Little v. Virginia Retirement System et al, 1992 (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Terry v. Wilder - George B. Little v. Virginia Retirement System et al, 1992 (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Terry v. Wilder - George Little v. VRS, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Hearing Proceedings, Dec. 17, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Memorandum of Criteria for Selection of Directors, VRS, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Misc., 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Misc. Correspondence to Governor, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Personal Notes, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Petition for Appeal, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Reports on Functions of Attorney General's Office, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Special Report of the Attorney General of Virginia on VRS, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Subpoena Papers, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Temporary Injunction Papers, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Terry v. Wilder - Virginia Retirement System, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Series II: General Files, 1988-1993., Extent: 1.75 cu. ft. (5 boxes). (Box 15-19)
  The General Files series is housed in 5 boxes, and is arranged alphabetically by folder title. The series consists of agreements, correspondence, court records, memorandums, newspaper clippings, reports, and other documents.
  - Administrative Law Judges, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - American College of Prosecuting Attorneys, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report - Virginia Consumer Protection Act, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Appointment of Attorney General - Constitution Amendment, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Arlington County Circuit Court, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Barr, John, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Baugh v. Judicial Inquiry Review Commission, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bizik, Michael H. 1988-1991 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Capital Punishment Defendants, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Constituents, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Cutler, Lynn, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Court of Appeals, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Dower, Albert, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Drunk Driving Legislation, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Expenditure of Lottery Funds for Newspaper Ads, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax Circuit Court, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - General, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Harp, Reno, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Hirshfield v. U.S. and Virginia, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Alsbrook, Carl Michael, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Boykin,Ivan, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Cutler, James Wallace, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Dodds, Christopher, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Ferguson, Michael, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Johnson, Dwain, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Kauffman, Nathan R., 1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Motors, Clayton, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Parker, Herman, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Peebles, Reginald, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers - Warren, Vincent, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Johns-Manville Asbestos Property Damage Bankruptcy Payments, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Judges, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Judges, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Judges - 3rd Circuit, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Judgeships, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Judgeship - 19th Circuit, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Judgeships - General, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Judicial Circuit Courts, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission (JIRC), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission (JIRC), 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission (JIRC), 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Judicial Salaries, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Law Review, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Legal Malpractice Insurance, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - List of Counsel, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Maddrey, Bobby R., 1991 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Media Coverage in Court Rooms, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Memo, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - National Association of Attorneys General, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - OAG Reappropriation of 92-93 General Fund Balance, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - O'Dwyer, Patrick Michael, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Olsham, Grundmand, Frome, Rosenzweig and Orens, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Presidential Authority, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Pully, Ashton - Law License, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Roanoke County Circuit Court, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Second Circuit Judgeship, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Second Judicial Circuit, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Sindram, Michael, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Special Grand Jury Reports, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Staffing Memo, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - State and Local Legal Center, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Stevens, Richard Leroy, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Supreme Court - General, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Virginia/Maryland Issue - Funds for College of Veterinary Medicine, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Virginia State University - Paul Alatorre, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Tech - Sale of Land, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Whitehurst, James L., 1992 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Wright, Mabel Frazier, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Series III: Subpoenas and Summons, 1990-1993., Extent: .53 cu. ft. (2 boxes). (Box 20-21)
  The Subpoenas and Summons series is housed in 2 boxes, and is arranged by year. The series consists of supboenas and summons issued to state government employees, related correspondence, and other documents.
  - Subpoenas, 1991-1992 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Subpoena - Dillard, Laura, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Subpoena - Johnson Mark L. v. Edward W. Murray, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Subpoena - Wilson, Joyce, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Subpoena - Adrian E. Wise v. Wilder, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Summons, etc. (Referred to OAG), 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Summons, etc. (Referred to OAG), 1991 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Summons, etc. (Referred to OAG), 1992 Jan.-Sep. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Summons, etc. (Referred to OAG), 1992 Oct.-Dec. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Summons, etc. (Referred to OAG), 193 Jan.-May (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Summons, etc. (Referred to OAG), 1993 June-Dec. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Series IV: Settlements, 19xx., Extent: 1.4 cu. ft. (4 boxes). (Box 22-25)
  The Settlements series is housed in 4 boxes, and is arranged chronologically. The series consists of correspondence, court records, memorandums, settlement agreements, and other documents. The records in this subseries are restricted for 75 years.
  Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78, 2.2-3800 and 2.2-3705.1-8. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: privacy protected information, mediation and settlement discussions, and attorney-client privileged material.
  - Settlements, Woodbridge Nursing Center, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Settlements, Miltier v. Beorn, et al, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Settlements, 1990 Jan.-June (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Settlements, 1990 Aug.-Sep. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Settlements, 1990 Oct.-Dec. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Settlements, 1991 Jan.-Feb. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Settlements, 1991 Mar.-Apr. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Settlements, 1991 Apr.-May (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Settlements, 1991 June-July (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Settlements, 1991 Aug.-Oct. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Settlements, 1991 Oct.-Dec. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Settlements, 1992 Jan.-Mar. (Box 23, Folder 5)